Guide to the Lewis F. White Photographs 1948-1952 PR 196
New-York Historical Society
Lewis F. White photographs
1948-1952
New-York Historical Society
White, Lewis F. (Lewis Felix), 1895-
PR 196
1 Linear feet (18 photographic prints: gelatin silver; 9.5 x 5 in. or smaller, on mounts 11 x 14 in.)
Mid-20th century views of popular Manhattan tourist destinations, including Central Park, Rockefeller Center, and St. Patrick's Cathedral.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lewis F. White, 1953.
Arrangement
Photographs are grouped alphabetically by location and thereunder by subject. Titles are the photographer's, except for those in brackets, which were supplied by New-York Historical Society staff.
Biographical / Historical
Lewis F. White (1895–1967), a book designer, typographer, and photographer, was the founder and head of L. F. White Company, Inc., a small printing firm based in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The Lewis F. White Photograph Collection spans the period from 1948 and 1952 and contains silver gelatin photographs taken in New York City. The photographs depict picturesque Manhattan sites and street life. Included are views of activity in Central Park, Rockefeller Center, a Greenwich Village art fair, and the Hudson River waterfront. Views of St. Patrick's Cathedral are also included. Each photograph is mounted, and each mount bears "Lewis F. White" in embossed type and has been captioned, signed and dated by the photographer.
Central Park (New York, N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.) -- Photographs.; Street life -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Gelatin silver prints.; Rockefeller Center -- Photographs; St. Patrick's Cathedral (New York, N.Y.) -- Photographs
- Central Park
  - Balloon Man. Central Park, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Central Park, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Central Park Lake, 1948 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Entrance to Central Park, 1951 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Popsicle Man. Central Park, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Terrace Café. Central Park Zoo, 1951 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Zoo Restaurant—Central Park, 1951 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
- Hudson River
  - Derrick. Hudson River, 1951 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dockside, Hudson River, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hudson River Docks, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - Tug Boats. Hudson River, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
- Rockefeller Center
  - Prometheus. Rockefeller Center, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sunken Plaza. Rockefeller Center, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
- St. Patrick's Cathedral
  - [Façade St. Patrick's Cathedral], 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - [Façade St. Patrick's Cathedral], 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous
  - Greenwich Village Art Exhibit, 1952 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - Plaza. New York [fountain], 1951 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ships, 1951 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)